<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://chrischoi314.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://chrischoi314.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2023-12-22T21:12:20+00:00</updated><id>https://chrischoi314.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">my slight obsession with long songs</title><link href="https://chrischoi314.github.io/blog/2023/formatting-and-links/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="my slight obsession with long songs"/><published>2023-12-22T15:50:35+00:00</published><updated>2023-12-22T15:50:35+00:00</updated><id>https://chrischoi314.github.io/blog/2023/formatting-and-links</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://chrischoi314.github.io/blog/2023/formatting-and-links/"><![CDATA[<p>Prog is short for progressive rock or metal, the genre of music that originated in the UK and the US with bands Pink Floyd and Procol Harum, and with progressive albums like Pet Sounds by the Beach Boys and Sgt. Pepper’s Lonely Hearts Club Band by the Beatles. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Progressive_rock">wikipedia</a> has a lovely introduction, but to briefly recount, it is a genre that constantly tries to push its boundaries, exploring novel insturmentation, time signatures, and chord progressions. 7/4 or 5/4 time signatures aren’t too uncommon, and particularly wild time signatures 11/8 appear <a href="https://youtu.be/zXdHNa0itZo?si=kID6NtCRcltkTLvS&amp;t=378">occasionally</a>.</p> <p>My own introduction to them was technically through Pink Floyd’s Dark Side of the Moon (I know, how original) on Feburary 28, 2017. It was shortler after I had discovered rock as a genre in general, and was riding high on my newly discovered bands like Radiohead, Queen, and the Rolling Stones. Besides that one album, however, I don’t believe I revisted prog until May 2, 2018, when I discovered The Ministry of Lost Souls by Dream Theater through this, admittedly snobby, <a href="https://youtu.be/wjkdGwHe5qg?si=1DzqvrFIRGPGe5nG">youtube video</a>. But what it had done was unlock this whole other world of music that I had never heard before. The Ministry of Lost Souls itself was no slouch; it’s 14:57 long and has some of the most iconic, haunting guitar riffs that goes on and on, continually modulating upwards until it famously “fades” out in its outro.</p> <p>I think this song definitely tinted my taste in songs permanently, since after that, I sought other songs with similarly grandiose melodies and durations. I present to you a list of all the songs in prog that I have since discovered and fell in love with. I have compiled as much as of these as I could into a <a href="https://open.spotify.com/playlist/2ROJq2mx5ZURHwV62GPQTP?si=b55e108ddf1946ff">spotify playlist</a></p> <p>Jean shorts raw denim Vice normcore, art party High Life PBR skateboard stumptown vinyl kitsch. Four loko meh 8-bit, tousled banh mi tilde forage Schlitz dreamcatcher twee 3 wolf moon. Chambray asymmetrical paleo salvia, sartorial umami four loko master cleanse drinking vinegar brunch. <a href="https://www.pinterest.com">Pinterest</a> DIY authentic Schlitz, hoodie Intelligentsia butcher trust fund brunch shabby chic Kickstarter forage flexitarian. Direct trade <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cold-pressed_juice">cold-pressed</a> meggings stumptown plaid, pop-up taxidermy. Hoodie XOXO fingerstache scenester Echo Park. Plaid ugh Wes Anderson, freegan pug selvage fanny pack leggings pickled food truck DIY irony Banksy.</p> <h4 id="hipster-list">Hipster list</h4> <ul> <li>brunch</li> <li>fixie</li> <li>raybans</li> <li>messenger bag</li> </ul> <p>Hoodie Thundercats retro, tote bag 8-bit Godard craft beer gastropub. Truffaut Tumblr taxidermy, raw denim Kickstarter sartorial dreamcatcher. Quinoa chambray slow-carb salvia readymade, bicycle rights 90’s yr typewriter selfies letterpress cardigan vegan.</p> <hr/> <p>Pug heirloom High Life vinyl swag, single-origin coffee four dollar toast taxidermy reprehenderit fap distillery master cleanse locavore. Est anim sapiente leggings Brooklyn ea. Thundercats locavore excepteur veniam eiusmod. Raw denim Truffaut Schlitz, migas sapiente Portland VHS twee Bushwick Marfa typewriter retro id keytar.</p> <blockquote> We do not grow absolutely, chronologically. We grow sometimes in one dimension, and not in another, unevenly. We grow partially. We are relative. We are mature in one realm, childish in another. —Anais Nin </blockquote> <p>Fap aliqua qui, scenester pug Echo Park polaroid irony shabby chic ex cardigan church-key Odd Future accusamus. Blog stumptown sartorial squid, gastropub duis aesthetic Truffaut vero. Pinterest tilde twee, odio mumblecore jean shorts lumbersexual.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="prog"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[march & april, looking forward to summer]]></summary></entry></feed>